<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on OPSXCQ Blog</title>
    <link>https://strm.sh/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on OPSXCQ Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 20:19:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strm.sh/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin address generation in pure python</title>
      <link>https://strm.sh/post/bitcoin-address-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 20:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strm.sh/post/bitcoin-address-generation/</guid>
      <description>Bitcoin address generation can be split in 4 steps listed bellow:
 Generating a secure private key. Calculate the public key from the private key. Encode the public key as a bitcoin address. Encode the private key in the WIF format.  Step 1: Generate ECDSA Keypair The very first step is to select a good and secure number, for this example we won&amp;rsquo;t use one, instead we will simply get the random from the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Programming</title>
      <link>https://strm.sh/post/linear-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strm.sh/post/linear-programming/</guid>
      <description>Linear programming is a mathematical method to achieve the best result for a given problem. This problem is expressed through a mathematical model which represents the real world problem. Also called linear optimization because of it&amp;rsquo;s essence to optimize a linear objective function.
In other words, linear programming aim to find the optimal input value for the function, value which will also be the optimal solution for the problem. Usually linear optimization is a good method to solve assignment problems which are a fundamental kind of combinatorial optimization problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>